Carlos Torres

SOFTWARE ENGINEER / www.carlostorresg.com

PROFILE

Senior software developer with 15 years of experience in modern web development for corporations and startups. Focus on TypeScript, Node, .NET, and Docker. Experienced in AWS and certified in GCP and Azure. Bilingual and fully fluent in English.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of CS

ITESO

PERSONAL DETAILS

Location

Guadalajara, MX (GMT-5)

Blog

www.carlostorresg.com

CONTACT

ctgovea@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/govea



@ctgovea

CERTIFICATIONS

Developing Solutions on Azure (AZ-203)

Google Cloud Digital Leader

ITIL Foundations Certificate

TRAINING

Developing and architecting on AWS

Docker Fundamentals

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

SUPERFORMULA

2022 -present

Built the backend on a digital marketplace for car enthusiasts using GraphQL, TypeScript, Terraform and Elasticsearch on AWS. Connected the backend to Contentful to manage admin data. In Contentful, created small React applications to add custom events and webhooks triggering lambdas.

Software Engineer & Startup Advisor

LIBERET / MENU LOCAL

2020-2022

Engineer #4 at Liberet, the first food social network in LATAM. Defined the microservices architecture using TypeScript, gRPC, DynamoDB and the Loopback framework. Created a CircleCI pipeline to build and deploy the React Native iOS app.

Tech Lead

JABIL 2016-2022

- Technical lead in Jabil's Connected Packaging initiative. Mostly developing in C# on a microservice event-driven architecture, using .NET Core, PostgreSQL and Docker containers on AWS ECS. Leading the Alexa skill development, certification and a dozen of developers working remotely.
- Built a chat-bot using the Microsoft Bot framework and integrated it into Microsoft Teams. Employees were able to query corporate information, send emails, and schedule meetings.
- Built a native Apple Watch Swift application from the ground up. The app reacted to certain hand motion. Used the Core Motion framework, Core Data, and the built-in messaging system for iPhone-Apple Watch communication.

Database Analyst II

JABIL

2013-2016

- Database developer in the global Jabil InControl team, a Gartner award-winning solution on the Supply Chain Innovation category.
- Improved and tuned performance, up to 40x, in the SQL Server database on procedures hitting +1.2 billion-row tables using columnstore technology.

SKILLS

TypeScript Node .NET Core Docker GraphQL SQL

AWS ECS DynamoDB PostgreSQL